Welcome back to AM Northwest. Our first guest
says Portland estate sales are a great place to
find historical treasures.
And here to show off some of his finds, we
welcome back antique appraiser Gary Germer.
Good to see you again, Gary. And by
the way, I have not grown a foot.
I'm standing on a pedestal here, as you
can see. This is how I'd normally be.
But in order to stand next to Gary,
who is 6'5", this is what we're doing.
So you've found some incredible
things over the time.
We have, and these are just some
Tammy, the producer, called.
Do you have anything interesting
in right now? And I do.
And Portland's a great city. In my
career, we've found amazing things.
But these are some of the ones I'm the most
excited about, starting with these autographs.
This, on the far end there, is
George Washington's signature.
Wow.
And it's actually right almost dead center.
And what that is is a ship's papers.
Oh, yeah.
So back then, if you had a ship and you
were going to fly the American flag,
you have to have it
approved by the government.
And back then, the
president would sign it.
So George Washington signed
it, and then on down.
And then he'd also sign
things like land grants.
He was really great on anybody who left the
Army, he would send them a letter and sign it.
Oh, okay.
So you'll find his autographs
on stuff like that.
And so when it comes to valuing autographs, it
depends a lot on condition of the autograph and
historical significance.
So something like this, you're going to find
more of them than, say, a handwritten letter that
he said,
hey, you know, on Tuesday at 4 o'clock we're
attacking, you know, or something like that.
And so those are the sort
of things that you can do.
This one here is John Hancock down here.
Literally.
John Hancock.
That's John Hancock's
John Hancock on there.
Yeah, that's cool.
That's really.
Okay, I've got to ask you,
how, where did you find this?
What estate sale?
This was up in.
I mean, the sales I go to, nothing
like this is going to be there.
Well, this is quite an amazing home.
The fellow who, the husband
was a real historian.
He was up in the West Hills.
Okay.
And a well-known family up there.
And then he had collected.
The family had kept some of the others.
They had Teddy Roosevelt.
We had others that
we're also dealing with.
These are the most, too exciting
that I'm currently dealing with.
That's just incredible.
Okay.
And down the line here
we have photographs.
These are by Ansel Adams.
Yes.
And if you probably have never heard of a
photographer, you probably have heard of Ansel Adams.
Yeah, everyone's heard of Ansel Adams.
And this is from a portfolio.
And a client came to me and she said,
Back in the day, her
husband had recently passed.
He was into photography.
And he had gone and taken a class by
Adams, who was teaching at the time.
And he'd do these seminars.
He was big in the Sierra Club.
He helped found the Sierra
Club and stuff like that.
Oh, that makes sense.
And so he made these portfolios.
So this is portfolio number three.
I think he did seven or eight.
I can't remember.
Portfolios.
So there's a portfolio
of 16 of his photographs.
So he took his favorite photographs
of Yosemite in this portfolio.
And they're all different.
They're all different images of Yosemite.
Wow.
They'll be signed by him.
He only made 208.
So in 1964, when he took the class, the
husband decided, I want a portfolio.
Yeah.
Paid 100 bucks for the portfolio.
No way.
Yeah.
And so then he decided, after he passed,
before he passed, he told his wife,
We'll take it to Gary and see if he
can't sell this for you afterwards.
And it's worth $70,000 to
$90,000 in today's market.
So are you going to sell it for her then?
Yeah, we're going to sell this for her.
If you don't.
Okay.
100% off because you're my friend.
Thank you.
Wow.
That's incredible.
Isn't that great?
Yeah.
And so there's 16 of them.
And they're old.
They're what are called
modern prints in 1960.
They were actually taken
from 1920 up to 1960.
And he chose his favorite 16
images of the Yosemite Valley.
That's great.
And that's what these are.
They're beautiful.
It's fun.
And he kept it perfect.
He kept it all stored away just perfect.
And then taking a look at the china.
And then this is also from northwest.
Let's see.
There's a whole.
I'm moving my box down, Gary.
Moving my box down.
Okay.
There we go.
This lady had a huge collection.
And we're dealing with a large, large
collection of Chinese export porcelains.
These date from the
1700s through the 1800s.
A lot of the patterns are very familiar.
This is like the blue willow.
They, you know, there.
But that's actually Canton.
Yeah.
still produce it and you kind of judge
these the age one of the ways of judging
the ages by how well painted they are
right and the vibrancy of the colors and
whatnot and what's gorgeous what's
interesting to me and just a little
trivia is that in the day back in late
1700s up through the 1800s the money was
with in in the trade was tea and silk
China this was inexpensive for them to
buy they would buy it by the crate
and fill the holes and use it as ships
ballast yeah and the ship
Yeah, and the ship can leak a little bit.
So this can be down where
it leaks a little bit.
It's not going to hurt it.
And then they kept the
tea and the silk safe.
And then they'd sell it
and it was beautiful.
You could also have your coat of arms like
this plate here has a family crest on it.
That's a little bit more.
You could order that and they
would bring it back for you.
So this is just a sampling of, I think she
has 400 pieces that we're dealing with.
Wow.
Incredible.
So give me some tips on where would you
go to when you see estate sales online?
So West Hills we know
is a good place to go.
I'm guessing Lake Oswego.
Lake Oswego, Dunthorpe, yeah.
And people who, yeah, so right?
Is that what you do?
Well, yeah, because these people, this set here,
and it depends on what you want to collect.
Define this without, I mean all three of these
people, well the photographer lady thought
this might be worth a thousand bucks.
Yeah, and that was something
she had for her husband.
Yeah, that was something she had.
These others they had collected, they knew
what they were, and they were looking for
a way to get a reasonable
price to liquidate.
So most of the time when I'm dealing with
an estate, I'm having to sell it at a fairly
reasonable price.
We're looking more like
auction prices than retail.
So you're going to get a good deal as opposed
to buying it from a high end store in New
York, which is if you want George Washington's
signature, you're going to have to go to a
high end dealer.
Whoa.
Okay.
Didn't pay the bill.
I guess they want me off the stage.
That's it.
Time to go.
All right, Gary, thank you very much.
Thank you, Dawn.
I appreciate it.
That was fun.